A Guide to the Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse, ca. 1940, 1943, and 1992-1995
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse 1940, 1973, and 1992-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-r,-s
This collection consists of ca. 550 items (3 Hollinger boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on June 19, 1999. The papers were purchased by the Library on September 11, 2003.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of Alan Cheuse, ca. 1940, 1973, and 1992-1999, ca. 550 items (3 Hollinger boxes) includes book reviews, short stories, articles, and essays, by Cheuse; an appointment book; correspondence, greeting cards, postcards, and electronic mail; articles about Cheuse and his books; manuscripts by Nicholas Delbanco, Josephine Carson, and other authors; printed material and broadsides about literary readings, conferences, workshops, and other events; an introduction of John Barth by Alan Cheuse; a file on his Smithsonian Study Tour lectures aboard the Cunard's Royal Viking Sun ship; a computer disk with the printed version of the short story "Hernando Alonso" by Alan Cheuse; cassette tape recordings; and page proofs of new pages for a reprint of The Light Possessed.
Contents List
- Appointment Book 1998 (Box 1)
- Articles about Alan Cheuse 1998-1999 (Box 1)
- Articles and Essays by Alan Cheuse (2 folders) 1992-1999, n.d. (Box 1)
- Biographical Information about Kristin O'Shee 1999 (Box 1)
- Birth Certificate of Alan Cheuse from the Perth Amboy General Hospital 1940 Jan 23 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (4 folders) 1995-1998, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence (2 folders) 1999 (Box 2)
- Cunard Lectures 1998, n.d. (Box 2)
- E-mail (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
- Greeting Cards, Postcards, and Invitations (2 folders) 1998-1999, n.d. (Box 2)
- Introduction of John Barth at the PEN/Faulkner Awards 1998 Nov 13 (Box 3)
- The Light Possessed by Alan Cheuse, page proofs of new front matter, new pages 8-9, and 108-109, and new back matter 1998 Mar 5 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Papers 1996-1999, n.d. (Box 3)
- Printed Material 1998-1999, n.d. (Box 3)
- Reviews by Alan Cheuse, alphabetical by title of book 1973, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
- Short Stories by Alan Cheuse 1984, 1998, n.d. (Box 3)
- "What You Carry" by Nicholas Delbanco 1998 Oct 10 (Box 3)
- Writing by Other Authors 1995-1999, n.d. (Box 3)
- No. 1) The Liar's Club Review, Hour Two, Diane Rehm on WMAU, American University, Washington, D.C. (T0021) 1997 Mar 21, audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)
- No. 2) Krakauer Into Thin Air Review, Hour Two, Diane Rehm, WMAU, American University, Washington, D.C. (T0021) 1998 May 15, audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)
- No. 3) Alan Cheuse Short Interview on "All Things Considered" National Public Radio concerning reviewing new books. (T0021) 1998 Fall, audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)
- No. 4) With Good Reason"Cover to Cover: Browsing New Books" by Mr. Roy, Virginia Tech and Alan Cheuse, George Mason University. (T0021) n.d., audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)
- Short Story, "Hernando Alonso" by Alan Cheuse, sent to The North American Review. (Disk 0007) 1998 Oct, COMPUTER DISK (Box 3)